Guide to the Office of Public Affairs, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of Public Affairs, Yale University, records
1951-1989
RU 238
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
The records consist of correspondence and program and administrative files of the Yale Office of Public Affairs. Included are records documenting the Yale Reports and the correspondence of Walter D. Littell, director.
Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-C (YRG 4-C), Records documenting public information functions at Yale University
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from Office of Public Affairs, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale University Office of Public Affairs, formerly the News Bureau and the Office of Public Information, publishes and distributes press releases, announcements, promotional films, and the Yale Bulletin and Calendar.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence and program and administrative files of the Yale Office of Public Affairs. Included are records documenting the Yale Reports and the correspondence of Walter D. Littell, director.
Universities and colleges -- Public relations; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
- Administrative files, circa 1950-1979; Accession 1981-A-027
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  The records consist primarily of material on the Yale Reports, a series of radio programs which featured Yale professors discussing contemporary issues, from 1958-1972 and correspondence 1951-1972. The correspondence documents the day to day operations and activities of the department.
  - Yale Reports
    - Transcripts and lists, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 5)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Yale New Haven Education Corp., application for federal grant, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
  - Radio and TV, general correspondence, 1951-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 12)
  - Yale Review, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Modern lithography article requests for info, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yale Political Magazine, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Finances, Yale alumni seminar, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - WGBH, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Film committee, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Director records, 1970-1990; Accession 1995-A-033
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025
  This accession contains the correspondence of Walter D. Littell, Director of the Office of Public Information. He was in charge of the corporate relations to the university, as well as, the Yale Weekly Bulletin and Calendar. The correspondence, which spans the period from 1980-1989, is divided into two sections: outgoing correspondence is in chronological order and correspondence with President A. Bartlett Giamatti. The entire accession is restricted until January 1, 2024.
  - Correspondence
    - Outgoing
      - 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 17)
      - 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18 - 35)
      - 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 36 - 46)
    - With A. Bartlett Giamatti
      - 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 47 - 61)
      - 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 62 - 74)